[Subtitles by danielsangeo]
Man, I don't get why that guy
didn't just run out of the room.
I guess he thinks he's bad ass
enough to take on the aliens
without the use of weapons.
That seems kind of stupid to me.
[glass shatters]
WHOA! Th...
Okay, first thing's first.
Did anything follow me?
No?
So, what the fuck is this? This
is what "containment" looks like?
Or, was he just carrying a
grenade and... tripped?
[vortigese]
Yeah, I can hear them!
THEY'RE ALREADY HERE!
Wow! This thing works great!
I don't know why the
inventor didn't want it.
[teleportation sound, vortigese]
What was that?
Ah hah!
[shudders]
Jesus...!
Okay...
So, I think what we can conclude here is
blue energy is superior to green energy.
And bees, but that was
already one of our assumptions.
Wuh-hoah!
GUARD: Sir?
I could've fried you,
but you're wearing blue so I
guess that's a sign.
Hey, you don't--yeah, I'm just
going to take this.
I mean, I don't see you trying
to stop me and I need that ammo.
GUARD: I'd like to get my hands
on the guy responsible for THIS mess.
Well, that's a complicated question.
I think Black Mesa has evolved
as a group consciousness
so that no individual truly
knows what he's doing.
Like this guy.
SCIENTIST: Freeman, isn't it?
Recognize!
SCIENTIST: You'll need to
activate both pumps
What? No!
SCIENTIST: to flood the reactor.
SCIENTIST: And then that the access pipe
down there will take you to the core.
No!
SCIENTIST: Time is short!
I'm not the maintenance man!
You have bad information!
And what reactor? Is this it?
The one with the big crack in it?
We're not on the same page here.
Look at me.
Actually, hold up, I'll take this
stuff off your hands for you.
Okay, so you just stay here and keep
staring at the wall. You're good at that.
[announcement klaxon]
PA: Biological force detected in
primary coolant system.
Biological force in the coolant system.
Well, there's the problem. An alien
must've teleported inside it.
GUARD: All that target range
time is going to pay off today!
Even down a magazine, huh?
Hey, I didn't notice that blood
stain before, Mr. Target Range.
Yeah, the splatter looks
like it came from here.
Holy shit! You shot
somebody, didn't you?!
I guess you're not a pushover;
that's not alien blood!
GUARD: I don't know if we should go
any further, th-this doesn't look right.
Yeah, I BET you don't me looking
any further into this!
But if you shot him, where's the body?
Oh, there he is!
So, you killed him.
Those aliens were just feeding on him.
Yeah, he's not even armed.
Wow, I'm going to watch
my back around here!
I don't want any surprises from
Captain Trigger Finger over there.
I mean, the other people who shot
at me, I mostly knew it was coming,
but this... shit!
Civilization's falling
apart pretty fast!
I mean, that's kind of scary, shooting
the scientist. I'm a scientist.
The guards aren't on our side,
they're on their side!
[metal groaning, rumbling]
Oh god!
This place is dangerous. And
nobody knows what they're doing.
There's probably going to be a
Congressional hearing about us later
asking, "How did this happen?"
And every single person is going
to say, "Uhhh... uhhh... uh..."
Okay, did that guard
shoot these guys, too?!
Do they have any bullet holes in them?
Actually, I don't want to know.
Some people thrive in chaos
a little too much.
Everyone else sees disaster, he
sees a human shooting gallery.
[teleportation sound]
Oh no!
Yeah, what, you're going to
cover up for him?!
I dunno. I've killed people, too!
But, the difference is I didn't kill
them BECAUSE they were alive.
I needed a reason...?
Daah!
Shhh...
I really like how the--
whoa, what was that?!
Somebody's up there!
I am SO certain I am not
hallucinating this time.
And I have a gun! I can prove it!
See?
SHIT! I'm spent!
PA: ...main reactor core...
Quit complaining about the reactor!
I found the contaminant!
Is he running from me?
This one has brains!
We can solve that problem.
[agrunt grumbles]
Shut up!
[explosion]
I wonder if he was filming me.
Well, I'm taking off this plasma pack.
It's amazing but I need to fire
it for MORE than 10 seconds total.
Gragh... that's better.
Yeah, it's a prototype. It only lasts for
10 seconds and weighs at least 50 pounds,
but, MAN, it makes things explode.
We could've sold it to the military
without any further improvements.
I especially I liked how the aliens
I hit with it became totally stunned
with this "Oh, my shit is
getting wrecked" face.
Okay, any surprises?
No.
[metal groaning, rumbling]
Oh, dammit!
I still think some of the aliens
are teleporting inside the walls.
PA: Danger...
Danger!
PA: ...detected in Radioactive
Materials Handling Bay.
[telportation sound]
Shit.
OH MY GOD!
OOOOOOOOOOH!
That one almost went inside me!
Aaaah...
PA: Cross-dimensional power
What?!
PA: field activity detected.
Cross-dimensional pow--no, wait.
What is this?
Okay. "No access." I believe them!
So... Oh, a switch.
Maybe this will fix... everything.
[telportation sound]
NO!
IS THAT WHAT THIS SWITCH DOES?!
Christ!
Okay, one more, I'm shutting it off!
I didn't know this was a monster
generator, that's a terrible idea!
Oh, this is just a pump.
I guess this is all just a
terrifying coincidence.
Jesus, I'm getting low on bullets.
I have one spare mag then I'm out.
The scientists probably don't
keep any spares on them.
PA: ...reports dimensional
contamination.
Dimensional contamination.
There we go again.
Whoever set up this intercom
system clearly wanted to fight me.
I keep hearing "dimensional power",
"dimensional contamination",
what the fuck are they talking about?!
I'm pretty sure these aliens are
three-dimensional!
Probably from somewhere deep in
space, but space isn't another dimension!
Does somebody here think they're
Buckaroo Banzai?!
But, okay, let's say that teleportation event
represents cross-dimensional activity.
How do we know this?
Have we figured all this out in
the past two days during a panic?
And, invented and set up cross-dimensional
detectors around the facility
like they're smoke alarms
AND set up a network-to-intercom
system to inform us when one happens?
If so, WOW! Color me impressed!
That's pretty good considering
your reactor is down
and you have a rogue security guard
dancing through the halls and
shooting your science team.
I wouldn't be able to get work
done under those conditions.
Silly me, I thought it was turning
into Lord of the Flies around here.
Okay, I've already been here...
Yeah, I guess this way.
But, yeah, these announcements
aren't fooling me. We're on the brink.
I bet if I wait a few hours and
then come back,
that security guard will be wearing
a necklace made out of ears
and painting pictures of demons or some crap
on the walls with the scientists' blood.
And then he's going to take--
[explosion]
[growls]
Well...
Shit...
Y'know, all this concrete dust
is a breathing hazard.